M.SEENI RAJA MOHAMED

1/575-15, Bhagawath Singh Road Bharathinagar, Ramanathapuram Contact No: +91-9940837202 Email:

seenirajamohamed@outlook.com

> Profile Summary

Highly skilled professional with nine years of experience in providing comprehensive technical support to end-users. Successful in installing, upgrading, and configuring innovative applications on Windows operating systems and providing technical support to optimize workflows and minimize business interruptions. Flexible to work in challenging environment as a genuine team member with own Initiative.

> Functional Skill Areas and Key Strengths

- Windows Server Installation.
- ❖ Active Directory Administration.
- ❖ Windows OS | MS Office | Lotus Notes IT Network component.
- Customer service oriented Good communication skills used to support various technical issues and desktop operation queries.
- Efficient problem solving and multi-tasking abilities.

> Professional Experience

Consolidated Gulf Company - Doha, Qatar Jul2017

Mar2016-

Desktop Engineer (Client QVC)

- ❖ Responding to requests for technical assistance in person via phone, Email and remotely.
- Creating tickets in Service desk plus ticketing system and followed up on tickets to provide resolutions for end users.
- ❖ Achieved 85% high first call resolution and 90% customer satisfaction rate.
- Installing, upgrading and troubleshooting Hardware, Windows OS, authorized desktop applications and peripheral equipment.
- Installing Backup System Images using Acronis Software.
- Optimize and standardize the handling of the antivirus system.
- Configuring and troubleshooting mail Clients such as Lotus Notes.
- Installing & supporting of software like Microsoft Office, Open Office etc.,

- Troubleshooting Network related issues.
- ❖ Attending calls of CEO's, VIP and Managers.
- ❖ Installing, configure and troubleshooting Printer, Avaya phone, Projector, etc.,
- Created Analyst performance reports and delivered them to senior management.

Global Computers - Ramanathapuram July2014- Feb2016

System Administrator

- ❖ Installing, upgrading and troubleshooting hardware and software applications.
- ❖ Coordinate and execute preventative maintenance and remedial repairs on computers, laptops, printers, and peripherals.
- ❖ Mail Clients configuration backup & troubleshooting MS Outlook.
- * Installing and configuring Windows Server, Domain Controller and DNS.
- ❖ Kept in constant touch with vendors to resolve problems as quickly & efficiently as possible.

Annai Fathima College of Arts and Science - Madurai Jun2013 - Jun2014

System Administrator

- Providing desk-side support for laptop and desktop computers.
- Performed general preventative maintenance tasks on computers, laptops, printers and any other authorized equipment.
- ❖ Deploy new workstations and printers and installed Windows OS, applications and configuring network.
- * Return defective equipment to maintenance inventory, document customer repairs and restock parts inventory to maintain spare parts levels.

CMC Limited - Chennai Apr2012

Feb2011

Desktop Engineer

- ❖ Handling daily technical support activities on Desktop support, Network and Server installation.
- Responsible for providing 1st level / 2nd level support to end-users in troubleshooting and resolving PC/Server problems.
- Configuring Microsoft outlook for user and troubleshooting Mail Problem.

- Provide training end users on usage of computers hardware and software
- ❖ Maintain inventory of installed software, manage software licensing and create policies and procedures for upgrades.

Wipro Info Tech - Chennai Dec2010

Dec2008

-

Desktop Engineer

- Installing, upgrade and troubleshooting hardware and software applications.
- ❖ Escalating relevant customer issues to the technical specialists and ensuring speedy resolution of the issues.
- ❖ Develop and manage effective professional working relationships with contractor personnel, co-workers and clients.
- ❖ Troubleshooting network connectivity in a LAN/WAN environment
- Preparation of Daily, Monthly and Timely Compliance report as per requirement.

Pioneer Hospital (P) Ltd - Ramanathapuram Mar2003 - Oct2007

Accounts Assistant

- Accounts Maintenance.
- Installed and troubleshoot all desktop and laptops.
- Installed and configured software.
- Hardware & Software inventory control.

> Educational Qualifications

- ❖ **Diploma in Computer Technology,** 2000-2002, Aggregate 80% First Class with Honors Mohamed Sathak Polytechnic, Kilakarai.
- Higher Secondary Certification (H.S.C), Apr2000, Percentage 60% Syed Ammal Higher Secondary School, Ramanathapuram.

Personal Details

Nationality : Indian

Date of Birth : 10th July 1982

Marital Status : Married
Language Known : English/Tamil
Passport No : M5814842

Skype ID : seenirajamd

SEENI RAJA MOHAMED